# **Anton Shirikov**

PhD Candidate, University of Wisconsin-Madison 110 North Hall, 1050 Bascom Mall, Madison, WI, 53706

☑ shirikov@wisc.edu **۞** shirikov.com | *Updated*: May. 28, 2020

I am a political scientist working on media, propaganda, and the mechanisms of authoritarian rule. I also study legacies of authoritarianism and contemporary political institutions in post-communist countries. My research primarily relies on surveys and experimental methods.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Wisconsin-Madison, Ph.D. Candidate in Political Science

In progress

Dissertation: Who Trusts Untrustworthy Media: Partisanship, News Consumption, and Information Credibility in Non-Democracies

University of Wisconsin-Madison, M.A. in Political Science

2016

Moscow State Institute of International Relations, Candidate of Sciences in Political Science

2007

European University at St. Petersburg, M.A. in Political Science

2005

### **PUBLICATIONS**

2020. "Eurasia and Post-Communism: Weasel Words?" East European Politics and Societies & Cultures, Vol.34, No.2. With Yoshiko M. Herrera and Dmitrii Kofanov.

2018. "Sovereignty and Regionalism in Eurasia." In: Paasi, Anssi, John Harrison, and Martin Jones (eds.). Elgar Handbook on the Geographies of Regions and Territories. Edward Elgar Publishing. With Dmitrii Kofanov and Yoshiko M. Herrera.

2013. "Public Administration in Russia." In: Liebert, Saltanat, Stephen E. Condrey, and Dmitry Goncharov (eds.). Public Administration in Post-Communist Countries: Former Soviet Union, Central and Eastern Europe, and Mongolia. Routledge. With Dmitry Goncharov.

2010. Anatomiya Bezdeistviya. Politicheskiye Instituty i Konflikty v Budgetnom Processe Regionov Rossii [The Anatomy of Inaction. Political Institutions and Conflicts in the Budget Process of Russia's Regions] (in Russian). Saint-Petersburg: EUSP Press.

### WORKING PAPERS

"Who Trusts State-Run Media? Source Cues, Bias, and Credibility in Autocracies"

"Is Trust in Media Decreasing? Evidence from the World Values Survey"

"Legacy of Communism and Trust in Media"

"A Model of Censorship and Propaganda" (with Scott Gehlbach and Dmitriy Vorobyev)

"Property Rights, Political Connections, and Defensive Ownership Strategies" (with John Earle, Scott Gehlbach and Solomiya Shpak)

"Smart Ways to Use a Postcommunist Dummy" (with Dmitrii Kofanov and Yoshiko M. Herrera)

"Legislatures and Executive Recruitment in Autocracies: Does Parliamentary Behavior Matter?"

# **CONFERENCES AND WORKSHOPS**

| Communication Crossroads (UW-Madison)  | 2020                      |
|--|---------------------------|
| Studying Russia and the Postcommunist World (Harriman Institute)   | 2019                      |
| The ASEES Annual Convention (San Francisco)  | 2019                      |
| MPSA Annual Conference (Chicago)   | 2019                      |
| The ASEES Annual Convention (Boston)   | 2018                      |
| Wisconsin Russia Project Young Scholars Conference   | 2018                      |
| Regime Evolution, Institutional Change, and Social Transformation in Russia: Lesso Science (Yale University) | ons for Political<br>2018 |
| MPSA Annual Conference (Chicago)   | 2018                      |
| The ASEES Annual Convention (Chicago)  | 2017                      |
| The Annual Meeting of the Society for Political Methodology (UW-Madison)                                     | 2017                      |
| Workshop on Research Design for Causal Inference (Northwestern University)                                   | 2017                      |
| RESEARCH EXPERIENCE  |                           |
| Research Assistant for Nadav Shelef (UW-Madison)   | 2020                      |
| Research Assistant for Scott Gehlbach (UW-Madison)   | 2016-2018                 |
| Research Fellow (European University at St.Petersburg)   | 2005-2006                 |
| TEACHING   |                           |
| University of Wisconsin-Madison  |                           |
| Lab and tutoring for PS919: Intro to Machine Learning  | 2020                      |
| Instructor: Adeline Lo   |                           |
| Math Camp for incoming graduate students in political science  | 2019                      |
| Teaching assistant for PS120: Politics Around the World  | 2019                      |
| Instructor: Nils Ringe   |                           |
| Teaching assistant for PS170: Research Methods in Political Science  | 2018                      |
| Instructor: Jessica Weeks  |                           |
| Teaching assistance for PS633: Russian Politics  | 2015                      |
| Instructor: Kathryn Hendley  |                           |

### **SERVICE**

Peer reviews of manuscripts for Post-Soviet Affairs, Problems of Post-Communism, East European Politics

Co-organizer of the **Comparative Politics Working Group** (UW-Madison)

2019-present

A regular workshop for graduate students aimed at sharing and discussing work in progress

Graduate student coordinator for the **Comparative Politics Colloquium** and the **Political Economy Colloquium** (UW-Madison) 2018-2019

A weekly meeting in the Department of Political Science where external and internal speakers present their work. Responsible for coordinating the visits and the everyday logistics of the colloquia

# **GRANTS AND AWARDS**

**ASEEES Summer Dissertation Writing Grant** 

2020

Summer Initiative Award (UW-Madison)

2020

CREECA graduate student research award (UW-Madison)

2020

A short-term research award by the Center for Russia, East Europe, and Central Asia to examine the perceptions of media in Russia

Harriman Institute Research Grant (with Georgiy Syunyaev)

2020

Research grant to examine the reasoning about media bias and its effects

Harriman Institute Research Grant

2019

Research grant to examine the credibility of news organizations in Russia

Summer Initiative Award (UW-Madison)

2019

Summer Initiative Award (UW-Madison)

2017

Summer Initiative Award (UW-Madison)

2016

### **SOFTWARE**

R, Python, Stata, LaTeX, RMarkdown, HTML, Shiny, Git

## **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

I have previously worked as deputy editor-in-chief and editor-in-chief at Slon.ru, as opinions editor at RBC, and as editor at McKinsey & Company (all in Moscow, Russia).